Summary

Seasoned front-end developer and web problem solver with more than 16 years of experience within the WordPress architecture, its APIs, and its ecosystem such as WooCommerce and Advanced Custom Fields. Developed and maintained many custom themes, plugins, third-party API integrations, dashboards, and post types to clients' designs and specifications, often working with designers and project managers. Well-versed in semantic and accessible markup with responsive styling as well as technical and client-facing communication.

Experience

${\bf Stovepipe}-{\bf Senior\ Web\ Developer}$

Richmond, VA / Remote

Full time: January 2015 to October 2024; Contractor: November 2024 to Present

- Produced dozens of custom plugins and responsive websites for clients of all sizes while coordinating to understand their needs, address issues, and provide progress updates.
- Designed and implemented a custom bulk pricing system in WooCommerce, complete with an artwork upload feature, bringing a glassware producer's customization process online to provide another avenue for sales.
- Seamlessly integrated a Virginia-based telehealth provider's proprietary API into their WooCommerce subscription system, enabling automation of post-checkout processes that previously required manual entry.
- Developed a post-to-PDF WordPress plugin for a major New York bank which enabled the automated creation of printable brochures of their services that would have otherwise needed manual creation and upkeep.
- Integrated a real estate API into the WordPress front and back ends for a major Virginia home builder, halving their property management workload by removing duplication of effort.
- Developed a real-time notification system within the WooCommerce back end for a Virginia landscaping supply company, decreasing their response time to new orders during their busiest times of the year.

RVANews.com — Web Developer and Strategist

Richmond, VA

- Summer 2008 to December 2014
 - Played a key role in managing and growing a local news web magazine with a small team, developing fully custom themes and plugins to support a network of local news websites.
 - Collaborated on planning and executing new features to enhance engagement, while continuously optimizing user experience and SEO using analytics and A/B testing.

PharrOut — Web Developer Summer 2008 to December 2014

Richmond, VA

Education

Virginia Tech — B.S., Computer Science; Minor, Mathematics September 2003 to May 2007

Blacksburg, VA

Skills

WordPress, WooCommerce, ACF, WPML PHP, HTML, Sass, CSS, SEO, MySQL, Drupal JavaScript, jQuery, Google Maps APIs Git, GitHub; Adobe applications, Figma